Have you seen these incredible new
images of our sun? What's truly crazy is
their scale. Zoom in further. Further.
The entire Earth would fit right here.
Keep zooming. The entire United States
could fit right here. What you're
looking at is swirling whirlpools of
plasma on the sun's surface, reaching
temperatures around 5,500°
C. Hot enough to make diamonds boil.
They're created by these crazy currents
where hotter material rises and then it
sinks as it cools. And these dark spots
are where those currents twist the sun's
magnetic field, releasing blasts of
energy, giant clouds of particles that
hit Earth, disrupting things like
telecommunications and our power grid.
Which is why this giant telescope in
Hawaii captured the sharpest image ever
of these plasma whirlpools. And now
they've got simulations based off them
to see how they move. But what if you
went even deeper into the sun? To see
that, subscribe.